<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How to do (almost) anything - Oleh Borys&#39; blog</title>
    <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/</link>
    <description>Recent content on How to do (almost) anything - Oleh Borys&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 11: Moulding and casting</title>
      <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week11/</link>
      
      <guid>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week11/</guid>
      <description>Moulding and casting a small figure and a circuit
Moulding and casting a small figure and a circuit Idea This week we had the opportunity to mould and cast some object that we would bring. I had two models:
A face of the devil made of sculpting plasticine, which my friend kindly lent me (thanks to Matvii). A circuit board from the watch bracelet I got at the club that could glow in different colors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9: Wireless connection</title>
      <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week9/</link>
      
      <guid>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week9/</guid>
      <description>Wireless Servo control using ESP32 and ESP8266
Wireless Servo control using ESP-NOW ESP32 and ESP8266 Idea I hope you enjoyed my previous project in Week 7, because this project is based on it. For the semestral project called Robotic arm control inteface I would like to transfer an Encoder position to the position of Servo, and of course it would be cool and convenient to do it wirelessly!
I came across a short video about the ESP-NOW protocol, I got interested and found out that it was a great way to connect two ESP boards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8: Large machining</title>
      <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week8/</link>
      
      <guid>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week8/</guid>
      <description>Milling a Saloon sign using a CNC
An American Saloon sign, milled on a CNC Idea This week we had the opportunity to use the CNC milling machine, so I took this chance to capture the famous meme about the US - &amp;ldquo;WHAT THE F*CK IS A KILOMETER&amp;rdquo; (eagle screech)
on a wooden Saloon sign like this
Model design Here is the model I designed in Fusion360
I decided to use all the wood available to me, so the dimensions of the sign are 50 x 30 cm (or 5 x 3 standart cheeseburgers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7: Actuators and output devices</title>
      <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week7/</link>
      
      <guid>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week7/</guid>
      <description>Testing max load of two Servomotors SG90 and their responce to an encoder
Servomotors max load and responce Idea As you can see in my Week 1 post, the semestral project is to create a Robotic arm control inteface. For this purpose we will need to use encoders which would transfer information to our motors copying the movements of the human arm. There was a mechanical rotary encoder Keyes KY-040 in our kit, so I decided to take it for testing, altough we will need to use something more advanced later like a magnetic rotary encoder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6: Sensors and input devices</title>
      <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week6/</link>
      
      <guid>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week6/</guid>
      <description>Creating Atari Breakout game on oled and lcd dispays
Atari Breakout game Inspiration I missed coding in C++, so this time I wanted to create a project where I would code a lot. A game is a great example. We&amp;rsquo;ve got a linear potenciometer in our JVC kits that can be used as an input for something. And I was hit by the idea: to replicate the old legendary classic - Atari Breakout game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5: Electronics manufacturing</title>
      <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week5/</link>
      
      <guid>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week5/</guid>
      <description>Creating a LED blinker with changeable frequency
LED blinker with changeable frequency Goal This week we soldered a predesigned circuilt &amp;ldquo;LED blinker&amp;rdquo; with changeable frequency that depends on the position of the trimmer. Our exercise was to put the components on the Universal Circuit Board as described on this scheme:
Preparation and soldering First of all, we will lay our components on the board and try to make as many straight connections between its legs as we can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Kinematic structures</title>
      <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week4/</link>
      
      <guid>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week4/</guid>
      <description>Creating Conveyor based on the Geneva linear mechanism
Conveyor based on the Geneva linear mechanism Preparation This week we learned how to create kinematic structures in Fusion360, especially using Add-on for creating gears.
I was inspired by the Linear Geneva mechanism
So I decided to create a conveyor based on the Geneva linear mechanism.
Model design Here is the model I designed in Fusion360
Model printing and cutting Firstly I decided to print a few parts to try they matches, especially the wholes for rotation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/about-me/</link>
      
      <guid>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Oleh Borys Contact Email: olehboures@gmail.com GitHub: CogniSeeker Location: Prague, Czechia Education Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree Czech Technical University, Cybernetics and robotics Prague, Czechia Lyceum Lviv physics and mathematics lyceum, Lviv, Ukraine Communication English (Pearson B2) Czech (UJOP B2) French (DELF B2) Ukrainian (Native) Russian (Native) Professional Profile Hi there! I&amp;rsquo;m glad to see you here. My name is Oleh, I am an ambitious student at the Czech Technical University who is passionate about technology and wants to contribute to the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Final project</title>
      <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week1/</link>
      
      <guid>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week1/</guid>
      <description>Creating a Robotic arm control inteface
Robotic arm control inteface Idea Main idea is to create an interface for human arm from shoulder to a hand that would cotrol a humanoid robotic arm with 3 joints.
Here are some pictures that would display somehow our idea. But please note that our arm won&amp;rsquo;t be able to control separated fingers because it would greatly complicate our model.
Inspiration Inspiration came from multiple futuristic games and films that tried in one way or another to implement an exoskeleton for a part or a whole human body and then control robotic arms huge robots on the distance or sitting inside of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: 2D Laser cutting and stickers</title>
      <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week2/</link>
      
      <guid>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a palm tree and a sticker of the Ramstein logo&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: 3D printing and scanning</title>
      <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week3/</link>
      
      <guid>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week3/</guid>
      <description>3D Printing Preparation This week we learned how to print models created in Fusion360 and sliced in SLicer afterwards. We used PLA filament and Prusa i3 MK3s, Bambulab A1 Mini FDM 3D printers.
We needed to print model that would be max 5cm^3, so it had an impact on my choice. I decided to create a universal watch stand that would suit for my watches.
Model design Firstly, I measured dimensions of my watch band and designed a model in Fusion360 and tried to do it the largest I could.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>