<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wood on How to do (almost) anything - Oleh Borys&#39; blog</title>
    <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/tags/wood/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wood on How to do (almost) anything - Oleh Borys&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/tags/wood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 8: Large machining</title>
      <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week8/</guid>
      <description>Milling a Saloon sign using a CNC&#xA;An American Saloon sign, milled on a CNC Idea This week we had the opportunity to use the CNC milling machine, so I took this chance to capture the famous meme about the US - &amp;ldquo;WHAT THE F*CK IS A KILOMETER&amp;rdquo; (eagle screech)&#xA;on a wooden Saloon sign like this&#xA;Model design Here is the model I designed in Fusion360&#xA;I decided to use all the wood available to me, so the dimensions of the sign are 50 x 30 cm (or 5 x 3 standart cheeseburgers).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Kinematic structures</title>
      <link>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//b232_b3b35jvc.pages.fel.cvut.cz/borysole/post/week4/</guid>
      <description>Creating Conveyor based on the Geneva linear mechanism&#xA;Conveyor based on the Geneva linear mechanism Preparation This week we learned how to create kinematic structures in Fusion360, especially using Add-on for creating gears.&#xA;I was inspired by the Linear Geneva mechanism&#xA;So I decided to create a conveyor based on the Geneva linear mechanism.&#xA;Model design Here is the model I designed in Fusion360&#xA;Model printing and cutting Firstly I decided to print a few parts to try they matches, especially the wholes for rotation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
